tamingthebeast.net 2013-03-23

# Privacy statement for Taming the Beast.net

|   
---|---  
  
Taming the Beast has created this privacy statement in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to privacy. The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for this website: [www.tamingthebeast.net](http://www.tamingthebeast.net/). For privacy issues pertaining to ringtones.tamingthebeast.net, you will need to review a separate privacy policy [available here](http://www.ringtones.tamingthebeast.net/privacy.asp). 

This statement is subject to change without notice and users of our service are expected to review this page on a regular basis. 

##  IP Address 

An IP (Internet Protocol) address is a unique identifier for a computer on a particular network; including the Internet. When you log on to the Internet, your computer is issued with an IP address. 

We use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server, for security purposes and to administer our Web site. Your IP address is used to gather broad demographic information. 

## Cookies 

The main purpose of cookies is to identify Internet users and possibly prepare customized [web content](http://www.webopedia.com/TERM/c/web_page.html) for them. They can be used for both benign and malicious means.  For a more concise definitions of cookies - [click here](http://www.webopedia.com/TERM/c/cookie.html)

We  use cookies to enable functionality of our message boards. Some of our content providers and advertisers do issue cookies. 

Third party vendors, including Google, use cookies to serve ads based on a user's prior visits to this website. 

Google's use of the DoubleClick cookie enables it and its partners to serve ads to users based on their visit to this site and/or other sites on the Internet. 

Users may opt out of the use of the DoubleClick cookie for interest-based advertising by visiting the [ads preference manager](http://www.google.com/ads/preferences/). (Alternatively, you can opt out of a third-party vendor's use of cookies for interest based advertising by visiting [aboutads.info](http://www.aboutads.info/).) 

## Links to other sites 

This site contains links to other sites. **Taming the Beast** is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Web sites. 

## Public Forums

This site makes chat rooms, forums, message boards, and/or news groups available to its users. Please remember that any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information and you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal information.  These forums are not monitored on a 24/7 basis, but if you feel that an item posted is offensive please send a description to michael at tamingthebeast.net 

## Security

This site has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control.  Details of our subscribers and classified advertisers are kept in secure areas of our server and with encrypted passwords. Security of our site is controlled in part by our hosting service - Thinkhost.  All activity on Taming the Beast.net is logged for security purposes. 

## Legal Issues

We may disclose personal information in response to a relevant legal process, for example, in response to a court order or in response to a law enforcement agency's formal request.

## Childrens' Usage

Taming the Beast.net strongly urges parents to monitor children's usage of the Web, including this web site. 

## Mailing lists 

Any visitor signing up for any of our in-house mailing lists are assured that we do not, under any circumstances sell, rent or otherwise redistribute our mailing lists to any other company. The only exception to this would be in the situation that Taming the Beast.net or a particular service area of Taming the Beast.net is sold to another party where mailing list subscriber information would constitute a part of that sale. 

## Premium ringtones services

Our premium ringtones services are powered and billed by Mediaplazza; as is customer data relating to our premium cell phone services - please [visit their site](http://www.mediaplazza.com/) for privacy and terms details. 

## Abuse/Inappropriate Communications

We reserve the right to forward abusive and inappropriate communications to the service providers of the originating communication and to relevant local, state, federal and international authorities. 

## Choice/Opt-Out

Our site provides users the opportunity to opt-out of receiving communications from us and our partners at the point where we request information about the visitor. 

This site gives users the following options for removing their information from our database to not receive future communications or to no longer receive our service. 

  * You can send email to michael at tamingthebeast.net 
  * Each email sent out contains a link at the end to allow for one-click unsubscribe 

## Correct/Update

This site gives users the following options for changing and modifying information previously provided. 

  * email michael at tamingthebeast.net 

## Other usability issues

You can discover more by clicking here. Please remember to also read our Disclaimer and Terms of Service notices - click here

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this Web site, we recommend you review our terms of service or you can contact 

Michael Bloch  Taming the Beast  [michael@tamingthebeast.net](mailto:michael@tamingthebeast.net) Box 112 Seacliff Park  South Australia 5049  +61 0404 284 011
